export const PHYSICSA2011 = [

{
id: "question1",
question:  "1. Which of the following factors affects the rate of diffusion of a gas?",
A: "Number of atoms",
B: "Mass of molecule",
C: "Viscosity",
D: "Surface tension",
answer: "B. Mass of molecule",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question2",
question:  "2. Two points Q and R in a room are specified by the coordinates (0, 0, 0) and (1, 1, 1), respectively. Determine the distance QR in metres.",
A: "1",
B: "√2",
C: "√3",
D: "3",
answer: "C. √3",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question3",
question:  "3. The relative density of ice is 0.9. This statement implies that when a given mass of ice melts the",
A: "volume of water formed would be 0.9 times that of the ice.",
B: "volume of water formed would be 0.9 more than that of the ice.",
C: "mass of water formed would be 0.9 times that of the ice.",
D: "mass of water formed would be 0.9 less than that of the ice.",
answer: "A. Volume of water formed would be 0.9 times that of the ice.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question4",
question:  "4. The pressure at a point in a liquid depends on the \nI. cross-sectional area of the vessel containing the liquid. \nII.- depth below the surface of the liquid. \nIll. — density of the liquid. Which of the statements above are correct?",
A: "I and II only",
B: "I and III only",
C: "II and III only",
D: "I, II and III",
answer: "C. II and III only",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question5",
question:  "5. Which of the following statements about viscosity is correct?",
A: "Engine oil is less viscous than water.",
B: "Viscosity is a property of liquids only.",
C: "Viscosity increases with rise in temperature.",
D: "Glycerine is more viscous than water.",
answer: "D. Glycerine is more viscous than water.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question6",
question:  "6. The motion of a body is uniform when",
A: "there is change in the direction of the body.",
B: "the speed of the body remains constant.",
C: "the rate of change of the velocity of the body is constant.",
D: "both the speed and direction of the body remain constant.",
answer: "D. Both the speed and direction of the body remain constant.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question7",
question:  "7. In which of the following distance-time graphs drawn above is the motion slowest?",
A: "I",
B: "I",
C: "Il",
D: "IV",
answer: "C. II",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question8",
question:  "8. The area under a velocity-time graph represents",
A: "final speed attained.",
B: "acceleration.",
C: "total distance covered.",
D: "work done.",
answer: "C. Total distance covered.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question9",
question:  "9. Which of the following quantities is a scalar quantity?",
A: "Magnetic field",
B: "Electric field intensity",
C: "Electric potential",
D: "Magnetic flux density",
answer: "C. Electric potential",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question10",
question:  "10. Two forces of magnitudes 30 N and 40 N act at an angle of 90° to each other. Calculate the magnitude of their resultant.",
A: "10.0N",
B: "20.0N",
C: "35.0N",
D: "50.0N",
answer: "C. 35.0N",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question11",
question:  "11. The energy in a light beam travels through space in concentrated packets called",
A: "electrons.",
B: "photons.",
C: "protons.",
D: "neutrons.",
answer: "B. Photons",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question12",
question:  "12. A uniform half-metre rule AB is balanced horizontally on a knife edge placed 20 cm from A and with a mass of 30 g at A. Calculate the mass of the rule.",
A: "20g",
B: "30g",
C: "120g",
D: "160g",
answer: "B. 30g",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question13",
question:  "13. A body executing a simple harmonic motion has an angular speed of 2 rads s7! and maximum displacement of 5 cm. Determine the magnitude of its acceleration.",
A: "0.ms?",
B: "0.2ms?",
C: "04ms?",
D: "0.5ms?",
answer: "B. 0.2ms²",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question14",
question:  "14. A force acts on a body of mass 20 kg and changes its speed from 20 to 30 m s. Calculate the magnitude of the impulse.",
A: "200 Ns",
B: "400 Ns",
C: "600Ns ’",
D: "1000 Ns",
answer: "B. 400 Ns",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question15",
question:  "15. The absolute zero is the temperature at which",
A: "water freezes.",
B: "molecular activity ceases.",
C: "the states of matter co-exist in equilibrium.",
D: "water has minimum volume.",
answer: "B. Molecular activity ceases.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question16",
question:  "16. Which of the following sources of energy is non-renewable?",
A: "Petroleum",
B: "Sun",
C: "Wind",
D: "Tidal waves",
answer: "A. Petroleum",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question17",
question:  "17. The moment of a force has the same dimensions as those of",
A: "efficiency.",
B: "momentum.",
C: "power.",
D: "work.",
answer: "D. Work",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question18",
question:  "18. A body 150 kg is raised through a vertical height of 5 m in 100s by a machine. If the efficiency of the machine is 80 %, calculate the input power. [g = 10 ms |",
A: "9.60 W",
B: "60.00 W",
C: "75.00 W",
D: "93.75 W",
answer: "B. 60.00 W",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question19",
question:  "19. The diagram above illustrates the set-up for an experiment on heat conduction. The experiment demonstrates that",
A: "ice is a poor conductor of heat.",
B: "water is a poor conductor of heat.",
C: "water can boil at any temperature.",
D: "ice is denser than water.",
answer: "A. Ice is a poor conductor of heat.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question20",
question:  "20. The following concepts are methods of heat transfer except",
A: "conduction.",
B: "convention.",
C: "convection.",
D: "radiation.",
answer: "B. Convention",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question21",
question:  "21. A given mass of gas at a pressure of 400 Pa has a temperature of 30 °C. If its volume remains constant, calculate the pressure at 40 °C.",
A: "533.3 Pa",
B: "413.2 Pa",
C: "387.2:Pa",
D: "300.0 Pa",
answer: "B. 413.2 Pa",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question22",
question:  "22. A metal of mass 200 g is heated from 60 °C to 75 °C. Calculate the quantity of heat supplied. [Specific heat capacity of the metal = 400 J kg'! K'']",
A: "1.08x 107J",
B: "1.20x 10°F",
C: "1.08x 1043",
D: "1.20x 1073",
answer: "C. 1.08x 10⁴ J",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question23",
question:  "23. In the lever system illustrated above, the effort required to keep the bar in horizontal equilibrium is",
A: "60N.",
B: "30N.",
C: "I5N,",
D: "12N.",
answer: "C. 15N",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question24",
question:  "24. Which of the following devices applies Pascal’s principle?",
A: "Lift pump",
B: "Force pump",
C: "Hydraulic press",
D: "Syringe",
answer: "C. Hydraulic press",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question25",
question:  "25. A progressive wave of frequency 20 Hz and speed 0.60 m s7 is reflected on itself from a rigid boundary such that the distance between a node and an adjacent antinode is x. Determine the value of x.",
A: "0.1200m",
B: "0.0600m",
C: "0.0150m",
D: "0.0075m",
answer: "A. 0.1200m",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question26",
question:  "26. When light from a source is propagated through a gas \nI.  certain wavelengths are absorbed. \nII. anemission line spectrum results. \nIII. dark lines are observed. Which of the statements above are correct?",
A: "I and II only",
B: "I and III only",
C: "IIand II only",
D: "I, II and III",
answer: "B. I and III only",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question27",
question:  "27. Aconcave mirror of radius of curvature 20 cm forms an erect image 15 cm from the mirror. Calculate the distance of the object from the mirror.",
A: "60.0cm",
B: "30.0 cm",
C: "8.5 cm",
D: "6.0 cm",
answer: "B. 30.0 cm",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question28",
question:  "28. In the diagram above, the refractive index of glass relative to air is",
A: "sin a/sin c",
B: "sin a/sin d",
C: "sin b/sin d",
D: "sin b/sin c",
answer: "A. sin a/sin c",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question29",
question:  "29. Total internal reflection of light occurs in a medium when the",
A: "angle of incidence for a ray in the denser medium is greater than the critical angle.",
B: "angle of incidence for a ray in the denser medium is equal to the critical angle.",
C: "angle of incidence for a ray in the denser medium is less than the critical angle.",
D: "ray is travelling from a less dense medium to a denser medium.",
answer: "A. Angle of incidence for a ray in the denser medium is greater than the critical angle.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question30",
question:  "30. Which of the following characteristics of the image formed by a diverging lens are correct?",
A: "Virtual and diminished",
B: "Realand diminished",
C: "Virtual and magnified",
D: "Real and magnified",
answer: "A. Virtual and diminished",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question31",
question:  "31. Light from an illuminated object passes through a converging lens and is reflected along its original path to form an image at the same position as the object by a plane mirror placed just behind the lens. If the distance between the object and the plane mirror is 20 cm, determine the focal length of the lens.",
A: "40cm",
B: "20cm",
C: "10cm",
D: "Scm",
answer: "A. 40cm",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question32",
question:  "32. The advantage of the Galilean telescope over the astronomical telescope is that in the Galilean telescope, the",
A: "final image is sharper.",
B: "angular magnification is greater.",
C: "field of view is wider.",
D: "final image is erect.",
answer: "D. Final image is erect.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question33",
question:  "33. A singer emits a note of frequency 200 Hz. Calculate the wavelength of the note. [Speed of sound in air = 340 ms'.",
A: "17.0m",
B: "6.0m",
C: "1.7m",
D: "0.6m",
answer: "C. 1.7m",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question34",
question:  "34. Echo is a phenomenon that shows that sound waves",
A: "are mechanical.",
B: "are longitudinal.",
C: "can be polarized.",
D: "can be reflected.",
answer: "D. Can be reflected.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question35",
question:  "35. Which of the following statements about force fields is correct?",
A: "Electrostatic, gravitational and magnetic forces are always attractive.",
B: "Electric, gravitational and magnetic fields obey inverse square laws.",
C: "Field lines are real but their corresponding fields are imaginary.",
D: "Field lines and their corresponding fields are both real.",
answer: "B. Electric, gravitational, and magnetic fields obey inverse square laws.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question36",
question:  "36. Which of the following statements about a satellite is/are correct? A satellite \nI.  describes a circle about the earth if its escape velocity is 8 km s7!. \nII. cannot escape from the earth’s surface with a velocity less than 8 km s7!. \nIll. describes an ellipse about the earth if its escape velocity is greater than 11 kms.",
A: "I only",
B: "Il only",
C: "I and II only",
D: "II and III only",
answer: "B. II only",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question37",
question:  "37. Which of the following expressions represents escape velocity?",
A: "2GM/R^2",
B: "√2GM/R^2",
C: "√2GM/R",
D: "2GM^2/R^2",
answer: "C. √2GM/R",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question38",
question:  "38. Which of the following observations occurs when a glass rod is rubbed with silk?",
A: "Electrons from the glass are transferred to the silk.",
B: "Protons from the silk are transferred to the glass.",
C: "Electrons from the silk are transferred to the glass.",
D: "Protons from the glass are transferred to the silk.",
answer: "C. Electrons from the silk are transferred to the glass.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question39",
question:  "39. Two point charges of 1.0 pC and 1.5 uC are 5.0 cm apart. Calculate the magnitude of the force between them. [(4ne, 7! = 9.0 x 10°N m? C*]",
A: "2.7N",
B: "5.4N",
C: "6.7N",
D: "7.0N",
answer: "B. 5.4N",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question40",
question:  "40. Two parallel plates separated by 15.0 mm have a potential difference of 2.0 kV between them. Calculate the electric field intensity between the plates.",
A: "13 xi1PNC*",
B: "3.0x10*NC!",
C: "Wxrienc*",
D: "4.5x10NC!",
answer: "B. 3.0x10⁴ N/C",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question41",
question:  "41. Using Kirchhoff’s first law for electrical circuits, the current in the 6 Q resistor in the diagram above will be",
A: "iti,",
B: "i, ~i,.",
C: "Bi",
D: "i,",
answer: "B. i₁ - i₂",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question42",
question:  "42. Four lamps labelled P(110 V, 100 W), Q(240 V, 60 W), R(250 V, 40 W) and S(300 V, 25 W) are switched on for the same duration. Which of the lamps consumes the highest amount of electrical energy?",
A: "P",
B: "Q",
C: "R",
D: "S",
answer: "B. Q",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question43",
question:  "43. Which of the following statements about a magnetic field is not correct?",
A: "A magnetic field is a region in which magnetic force is experienced.",
B: "The resultant magnetic field of two fields is zero at neutral points.",
C: "A magnetic field is produced by electric charges in motion.",
D: "The magnetic field around a bar magnet is of uniform strength.",
answer: "D. The magnetic field around a bar magnet is of uniform strength.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question44",
question:  "44. The efficiency of a transformer can be increased by",
A: "making the core with soft magnetic material.",
B: "increasing the eddy current.",
C: "increasing the resistance of the copper coil.",
D: "increasing the primary voltage.",
answer: "A. Making the core with soft magnetic material.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question45",
question:  "45. The current in the primary coil of an ideal transformer is 2.5 A. If the primary coil has 50 turns and the secondary 250 turns, calculate the current in the secondary coil.",
A: "0.2A",
B: "0.5A",
C: "5S.0A",
D: "100A",
answer: "B. 0.5A",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question46",
question:  "46. A resistor, an inductor and a capacitor are connected in series to an a.c. supply. At resonance, the impedance of the circuit is",
A: "maximum.",
B: "equal to zero.",
C: "equal to the resistance in the circuit.",
D: "equal to the reactance in the circuit.",
answer: "C. Equal to the resistance in the circuit.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question47",
question:  "47. When temperature of an intrinsic semiconductor is increased above room temperature it will have",
A: "more electrons than holes.",
B: "more holes than electrons.",
C: "noelectrons crossing the forbidden band.",
D: "equal numbers of electrons and holes.",
answer: "D. Equal numbers of electrons and holes.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question48",
question:  "48. The energy of the ground state of a hydrogen atom is -13.6 eV. Calculate the energy associated with the third energy level.",
A: "4.54 eV",
B: "-1.51 eV",
C: "+4.53 eV",
D: "+40.80eV",
answer: "B. -1.51 eV",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question49",
question:  "49. A nuclide X of atomic number 92 and mass number 235 decays to a nuclide Z by emitting two beta-particles and one alpha particle. Which of the following correctly represents Z?",
A: "231/88 Z",
B: "231/90 Z",
C: "233/88 Z",
D: "231/92 Z",
answer: "B. 231/90 Z",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question50",
question:  "50. The radiation emitted by a radioactive sample has momentum, a fairly high penetrating power and can be deflected by a magnet. The radiation is most likely to be",
A: "analpha particle.",
B: "a beta particle.",
C: "gamma ray.",
D: "x-ray.",
answer: "B. A beta particle.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},


]